Guide to the Jack Durham papers, 1850-1985 MS2053
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about regional organization, with enclosure, 1967 April 02 (Box 6, Folder 65)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, with enclosure, 1967 June 23 (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1967 July 01 (Box 6, Folder 67)
- Letter from Benton to Ethel Durham, 1967 November 21 (Box 6, Folder 68)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S Durham about PATC 40th Anniversary, 1967 December 10 (Box 6, Folder 69)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham with two enclosures, 1967 December 22 (Box 6, Folder 70)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about PATC 40th Anniversary, with two enclosures, 1967 December 25 (Box 6, Folder 71)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1968 February 08 (Box 6, Folder 72)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about proposed Three Sisters Bridge, with enclosure, 1968 February 16 (Box 6, Folder 73)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about proposed Three Sister, with enclosure, 1968 March 04 (Box 6, Folder 74)
- Letters from Burton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about the death Harvey Prone, with two enclosures, 1968 March 24-April 14 (Box 6, Folder 75)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to Durham tribe, 1968 July 28 (Box 6, Folder 76)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1968 October 07 (Box 6, Folder 77)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to Ethel Durham, undated (Box 6, Folder 78)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to Ethel Durham, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 79)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about possible articles for National Geographic Society, in the enclosure, 1969 January 10 (Box 6, Folder 80)
- "First of the great foresters" article by Lee Wood with photos in The Lowell [Mass.] Sun, 1969 December 07 (Box 6, Folder 81)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye C.J.S. Durham, 1969 December 10 (Box 6, Folder 82)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1970 March 14 (Box 6, Folder 83)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1970 April 02 (Box 6, Folder 84)
- Last will and testament of Benton MacKaye, 1970 June 13 (Box 6, Folder 85)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1970 August 11 (Box 6, Folder 86)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1970 August 26 (Box 6, Folder 87)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham mentioning possible publication & "The Fifth Resource", 1970 September 14 (Box 6, Folder 88)
- Note from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham with two annotated copies "The Fifth Resource" article by Benton MacKaye, undated (Box 6, Folder 89)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1970 September 29 (Box 6, Folder 90)
- "American Forests" vol. 77 no. 2 illustrated containing "Long, Long Trail a winding" illustrated article by Penny Whitley, undated (Box 6, Folder 91)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1968 September 13 (Box 6, Folder 92)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1968 September 08 (Box 6, Folder 93)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about Walter J. Hickel as Secretary of the Interior, with enclosure, 1969 February 08 (Box 6, Folder 94)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1969 October 26 (Box 6, Folder 95)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham with enclosure, 1969 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 96)
- The Living Wilderness Vol. 33 No. 105 containing reviews by C.J.S. Durham of "Expedition Nine" by Benton MacKaye, Spring, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 97)
- Videocassette, 1980 January 23 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1971 March 11 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham with enclosure, 1971 March 16 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1971 December 25 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- "Citizens Show Concern on Booming US Theme Park Industry" article by Claudia Levy in The Washington Post, 1973 March 16 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1973 March 26 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Memorandum from Paul H. Gehser to C.J.S. Durham, with enclosure, 1973 April 04 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham, 1973 June 09 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to Durham Tribe, Circa 1973 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Letter, annotated from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham with reunions came about Douglas C&O Hike, 1974 March 19 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- "Langerity" anonymous poem with addition by Benton MacKaye, and C.J.S. Durham, 1969 March-1975 June 03 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham with enclosure, 1975 July 22 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Benton MacKaye obituary by C.J.S. Durham with biographical notes by Michael Nadel & remarks by Lewis Mumford Dec., 1975 December (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Invitation from the Appalachian Trail conference and the Wilderness Society to memorial service for Benton MacKaye, 1976 March 24 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- The Living Wilderness, vol. 39, no. 132 with MacKaye bibliography, photos, and tributes by many conservation notables, 1977 January 03 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- "On Benton MacKaye's Centerary" articles by Paul H. Gehser in The Living Wilderness, Circa 1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- "The Forest Community" outline for article or book by Benton MacKaye, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Windsor to Hilltop shelter map, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about proposal publication on the Geotechnics of North America by the U. of Illinois Press, with two enclosures, 1965 September 25 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about the proposal publication of The Geotechnics of N. America by the university of Illinois Pres. w/our four enclosures, 1966 January 23 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Memorandum from Benton MacKaye to C.J. S. Durham with enclosure, 1966 June 20 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about editing of The Geotechnics of N. America w/enclosure, 1966 August 04 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about editing The Geotechnics of N. America, 1966 August 17 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about proposal publication of The Geotechnics of N. America with two enclosures, 1966 August 20 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham with enclosure, 1970 January 25 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham mentioning that M.I.T. press has rejected book on geotechnics, 1970 February 19 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about rejecting The Geotechnics of N. America by M.I.T. Press, with two enclosures, 1970 March 01 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Letter from Benton MacKaye to C.J.S. Durham about inability to find publishers for Geotechnics of N. America, with three enclosures, 1970 November 17 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- A Two-year career in Geotechnics brochure by Benton MacKaye, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Forecast newsletter PATC vol. X no. 10, 1956 October (Box 8, Folder 29)
- "Protecting Dedicated Areas from Encroachment" articles in Recreation, reprinted by the Nature Causeway as Information Bulletin no. 27, 1957 June-1958 May (Box 8, Folder 30)
- "The Lost Colony Lives Again" article by Allen and Martha Rankin in Theatre Arts,, as condensed in The Reader's Digest, 1956 July-Circa 1957 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- "Study Finds Spread of Cities Changing Living in U.S. and Creating New Problems" article reprinted from The New York Times, Circa 1957 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Nature Conservancy News vol. 8, no. 2, 1958 May (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Letter from Mrs. C.D. Shoemaker, Chairman Conservation Committee, National Capital Garden Club League Inc., to Mrs. N.N. Benson, Administrative Assistant National Park Service with enclosure, 1959 May 18 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Letter from Charles Ogburn Jr., to Jack Durham about Virginia parks, 1960 September 22 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Letter from O.F. Bennett, Assistant to the Director of the Nature Conservancy, to Jack Durham about Conservancy membership, 1962 September 05 (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Small bowl with the Chesapeake & Ohio Canal Company seal, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Box of old fashioned cut nails from the Tremont Nail Co., undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Slides: Douglas reunion hike, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 13)